### Shun-Yi Jheng

m157q.tw@gmail.com | https://blog.m157q.tw | https://www.linkedin.com/in/shunyi

### **SUMMARY**

Keep participating conferences and meetups in Taiwan since college.<sup>[1]</sup> Love to share experiences and insights I've learned during troubleshooting on my blog or giving tech talks in confs and meetups.<sup>[2][3]</sup> Was a member of team BambooFox at NCTU, participated in several CTF competitions and other infosec events.<sup>[4]</sup> Currently focus on DevOps and web service performance optimizations with intensive Python tooling and technologies, such as Django, Flask, Celery.<sup>[5]</sup>

### **EXPERIENCES**

Tagtoo Taipei, Taiwan

Service Architect & DevOps

January 2016 — November 2017

- Save 70% cloud platform service expense in 3 months after joined the company.
- Speed up Travis CI testings by 6x (overall time).
- Reorganize inbound traffic data flow for easier tracing on troubleshooting (integrated with Stackdriver monitoring tools).
- Refine user tracking data collection (~12M pageviews per day) with MapReduce on Google App Engine and boost backend performance up to 33% faster.
- Contribute to Travis-CI's Google App Engine continuous deployment pipeline (written in Ruby). [6]
- Enable automatic web frontend static assets deployment on CDNs.
- Redesign service architectures with RESTful API microservices on Docker/Kubernetes to avoid single point of failure and provide high availability.
- Create whole-site documentations of interconnections between individual components in a high-level perspective.
- Collaborate with peers (engineers and non-engineers) on communications to help them be mutually intelligible to each others.
- Tech stacks: Python (Django, Flask, Celery), Containers (Docker, Kubernetes), Databases (MySQL, SQLite, Redis), Cloud Services/Platforms (Google Cloud Platform, CloudFlare, Travis CI, GitHub, Trello, Slack), Git.

# Computer Center of Dept. Computer Science, NCTU

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Linux, Web & PC team

August 2013 — July 2015

- Undergraduate teaching assistant of Computer System/Network Administration courses.
- Pratical experiences: legacy system improvement, database administration, web development.
- Tech stacks: Linux (Arch, Debian, Gentoo, Ubuntu), FreeBSD, Bash, Virtualization (VMware ESXi, Xen), software RAID storage systems (Btrfs, ZFS, mdadm), PHP (Yii, CodeIgniter), Python, Perl, MySQL, Clonezilla, Hardware Operations.

# **Open House, NCTU**

Hsinchu, Taiwan

IT team

September 2012 — May 2014

- Refactor and modularize the legacy code to be more maintainable.
- Tech stacks: PHP (Yii), Arch Linux, Nginx, Apache, QEMU, ZFS, MySQL, mdadm, crontab, Git.

### **EDUCATION**

# **National Chiao Tung University**

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Bachelor of Computer Science

September 2011 — June 2015

• Information and Communication Security Credit Programme

- Relevant Courseworks
  - Computer System/Network Administration (A+), FOSS and Project Collaboration (A+)

# **PROJECTS**

Android Repackaged App Detection System<sup>[7]</sup>

August 2013 — January 2015

- Program slicing, subgraph isomorphism, obfuscation tricks and Android app reversing.
- Tech stacks: Python (NetworkX, Scrapy), JavaScript (Node.js, D3.js), Perl, Java (SAAF), smali, Git.

#### **HONORS**

- 2015 4<sup>th</sup> place in Taiwan Student Cluster Competition. [8]
- 2013 5<sup>th</sup> place in Golden Shield Information Security Contest.<sup>[9]</sup>

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

English (TOEIC 840/990 in 2011, GEPT High-Intermediate prelim in 2011), Mandarin

#### REFERENCES

- 1. https://blog.m157q.tw/category/confmeetup/
- 2. https://blog.m157g.tw/category/talk/
- 3. https://blog.m157q.tw/category/note/
- 4. BambooFox
  - https://ctftime.org/team/9871
  - A security team consists of NCTU students and alumni, mainly focusing on CTF competitions and security related issues.
- 5. Some of my side projects written in Python:
  - https://github.com/M157q/zdict
    - A cross-platform CLI tool to query online dictionaries with Docker and syntax highlighting support.
  - https://github.com/M157q/gettitle
    - A CLI tool to get the title of the webpage with JavaScript support by using Selenium.
  - https://github.com/M157g/hor2vec
    - A CLI tool to change your horizontal pure text to vertical with some options.
- 6. https://github.com/travis-ci/dpl/pulls?utf8=%E2%9C%93&q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclose+author %3AM157q
  - Shortened URL: https://goo.gl/Gzz6m2
- 7. https://github.com/M157g/Android-Repackaged-App-Detection-System
  - Slides: https://speakerdeck.com/m157q/sitcon2015-android-repackaged-app-detection-system
- 8. http://event.nchc.org.tw/2015/tscc/index.php?CONTENT\_ID=25
  - Shortened URL: http://goo.gl/80SZjB
  - Team Name: 幼稚鬼團與他的快樂夥伴
- 9. http://www.nicst.ey.gov.tw/News\_Content4.aspx?
- n=11EC3BA2351F93AA&sms=4D833E26864BB926&s=4C2DD1B0FA325D80
  - Shortened URL: http://goo.gl/oUfJqK
  - Team Name: 聽說名字太長躲在防火牆